# **RUSS TRACY**

South Weber, UT 84405

Phone: (801) 628-9257 | E-mail: russ\_tracy@comcast.net
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/russtracy | GitHub: https://github.com/RussTracy
Portfolio: https://russtracy.github.io/Russ-Portfolio/

#### **Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer who has been consistently praised as quality-oriented by my co-workers and management. Strong knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery. Experienced in working with other developers remotely to accomplish desired results. Have consistently demonstrated teamwork, problem-solving and interpersonal abilities in every aspect of my previous role as a web developer.

#### Skills

**Languages:** HTML - JavaScript - CSS - Git - MySQL - jQuery - Bootstrap - API's - Ajax - Node - Express.js - C# - MVC.net - XML - XSL - JSON

**Applications:** Microsoft Suite - Adobe Photoshop - Visual Studio - WalkMe - Visio

# Experience

# Web Developer II Marriott International

2017 - 2020 Salt Lake City, UT

- Developed a complex software application to track VDN numbers for the telecommunication department.
- Engineered PCI redaction triggers using 3rd party software, preventing recording of personal information during customer phone calls.
- Designed and implemented WalkMe solutions to enhance ongoing user training.
- Conducted review testing of various web applications for responsiveness and clarity.

# Web Developer I Marriott International UT

2011 - 2017 Salt Lake City,

- Converted 22,000 page information application to new web platform, providing a 10% increase in efficiency.
- Redesigned information web application to include JavaScript/jQuery and SQL Database functionality, resulting in improved dissemination of complex hotel information.
- Conducted QA testing over course of web development lifecycle, resulting in increased site useability.
- Developed new scripts to allow for better navigation of current websites, resulting in a 5% drop in call times.

# Intranet Content Administrator Marriott International UT

2001 - 2011 Salt Lake City,

- Reviewed incoming change requests to verify content with company guidelines, increasing consistency of information provided to guests.
- Modified 50+ articles per week with a 24 hour turnaround requirement, increasing accuracy of information provided to guests.
- Upgraded an 15,000 page internal information system to a web-based application using HTML and inline CSS, assisting 1,000+ customers in several satellite offices world wide.
- Established streamlined CSS files to improve efficiency of web-based information systems, resulting in 75% reduction in written code.

# **Projects**

#### Can I Bike

Web app providing information on city bike rentals as well as local weather conditions.

**Role:** Setting up API calls to import data into site.

**GitHub** - https://github.com/hunterstrunk/can-i-bike

**Site** - https://hunterstrunk.github.io/can-i-bike/

Technology: HTML, CSS (Bulma), JavaScript, Open Weather API, City Bikes API

#### Education

October 2020 - April 2021

University of Utah - Coding Boot Camp, Full Stack Web Developer

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

2007 - 2009

Western Governors University - Information Technology

# **Licenses & Certifications**

# **Certified Internet Web Professional Web Foundations Associate (CIW)**

Issued Aug 2007 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID 306020

# **Certified Internet Web Professional JavaScript Specialist (CIW)**

Issued Sep 2009 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID 306020

# Certified Internet Web Professional v5 Associate (CIW)

Issued Aug 2007 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID 306020

# CompTIA A+

Issued Jul 2009 (Western Governors University)
Credential ID COMP001008900888